原創翻譯  雙語字幕
最新連載海外影視劇下載
請登陸 www.YYeTs.com
僅供交流學習  禁止商用盈利
翻譯     小酸奶  白夜君
校對     小酸奶
時間軸     西·查  小式
后期     吉吉
總監     小酸奶
深入黑暗
第一季第三集
謎怪
看看這璀璨的燈光
Look at all the pretty lights.
您好  您能幫我們照張相嗎
Hey, would you mind taking our picture?
當然可以
Oh, um, of course not.
來  靠近點
Okay, don't miss it.
-茄子  -茄子
- Cheese! - Cheese!
-真好  -是啊
- That's great. - Yeah.
非常感謝您
Hey, man, thank you so much, dude.
-圣誕節快樂  -圣誕節快樂
- Merry Christmas. - Merry Christmas.
演員招募
您好
Hello!
您好  很抱歉
Hi, I'm so sorry,
我是您隔壁的鄰居
I'm your next door neighbor
我忘帶鑰匙了
and I think I've locked myself out.
您能幫我開下門嗎
Do you mind letting me in?
您好
Hi.
我是威爾遜
I'm Wilson.
您剛幫我開的門
Uh, you buzzed me in downstairs.
你剛搬進來嗎
You just moved in?
是的
Right.
請進
Well, come on.
請進吧
Come on in.
謝謝您
Well, thank you.
你口渴嗎
Are you thirsty?
你看起來口渴
You look thirsty.
我沒事  謝謝
I'm all right, thanks.
人們一般不會讓陌生人進門的
People don't usually let strangers in.
你知道的
You know?
可能會很危險
It can be dangerous.
其實
Well...
自己一個人住也很危險
it can be dangerous being alone too.
我剛剛還在擔心自己一個人過圣誕
I was just worrying about being all alone
突然間
for Christmas, and poof!
你出現了
You appear.
突然之間
Poof.
我是雷德
I'm Red.
來自隔壁的威爾遜
So, Wilson from just next door,
你是這兒的人嗎
are you from around here?
我不是
I'm not.
那你來城里干什么
Oh, well, what brings you to town?
我也不知道
I'm not really sure.
我是來重新開始的吧
I'm...starting over, I guess.
白紙一張
Blank slate.
你有工作了嗎
Are you employed?
算吧
Sort of.
算是吧
Sort of...
我猜  我是個演員
I'm an actor, I guess,
所以我猜我在演戲
so I--I guess I'm acting.
一位演員
Oh, an actor!
我像羽毛一樣輕盈
I'm as light as a feather
像天使一樣高興
and happy as an angel.
像女學生一樣快樂
I'm as merry as a schoolgirl
像醉漢一樣暈眩
and as giddy as a drunkard.
你也是嗎
You too?
我也輝煌過
I had my moment.
可早就逝去了
It's long gone now.
我對你很有好感
I have a good feeling about you,
來自隔壁的威爾遜
Wilson from just next door.
現在是你的時代
This is your moment.
還沒有逝去
It's not gone for you.
在我面前的
"Am I in the presence
是未來的圣誕節鬼靈嗎
of the Ghost of Christmas Yet to Come?"
你是我見過的最讓人...
"I fear you more than any spec...?
讓人恐懼的怪物
specter I have seen."
這么說很蠢
No, that's shit.
蠢極了
It's fucking shit. Okay, um...
查爾斯·狄更斯《圣誕頌歌》
在我面前的
"Am I in the presence
是未來的圣誕節鬼靈嗎
of the Ghost of Christmas Yet to Come?
你是我見過的最讓人恐懼的怪物
I fear you more than any specter I have seen.
但當我知道你并無惡意
But as I know your purpose is to do me good,
我準備好接受你的陪伴
I am prepared to bear your company
并懷有一顆感恩之心
and do it with a thankful heart.
但在我走近
But before I draw nearer
你指的那塊石頭之前
to that stone to which you point,
回答我一個問題
answer me one question."
這將是未來的影子
"Are these the shadows of the things that will be
還是獨一無二的影子
or are they the shadows of the things that may be only?
人們走的路將預示著他們的結局
Men's courses will foreshadow
如果堅持下去
certain ends to which, if persevered in,
他們必須主導
they must lead,
但如果路線偏離
but if the courses be departed from,
結局將被改變
the ends will change.
你所指示我的
Say it is thus
我也要這樣說
with what you show me.
我是那個躺在床上的男人嗎
Am I that man who lay upon the bed?
我是那個躺在...
Am I that man who lay...
威爾遜·克勞斯
Wilson Klaus?
您好
Hi.
請開始吧
Your mark, please.
到中間去
It's in the center.
好的
Okay.
抱歉
Sorry.
好吧
Okay.
在我面前的是未來的圣誕節鬼..
"Am I in the presence of the Ghost of Christmas Yet to...?"
好的  可以了  謝謝你
Okay, that's fine, thank you.
剛才那是獨白
That--that was the monologue?
已經可以了
It's fine.
我做錯什么了嗎
Did I do something wrong?
我...
I'm...
我可以換一種形式
I can do it differently.
沒這個必要了
That won't be necessary.
你...確定嗎
Are you...sure?
把胳膊舉起來
Raise your arms up.
抱歉  你說什么
I'm sorry, what?
把胳膊舉起來
Raise your arms up.
-好吧  -再高點
- Okay. - Higher.
把手并在一起  擺成一個三角形
Now together like a triangle.
不  要放在你面前
No, in front of your face.
擺一個供奉的姿勢
Now out like an offering.
什么
A--a what?
供奉的姿勢
Like an offering.
擺一個飛機的姿勢
Now fly like a plane.
轉身
Turn around.
擺一個飛機的姿勢  然后轉過去
Fly like a plane and turn around.
把胳膊舉起來
Raise your arms up.
擺成一個三角形
Together like a triangle.
擺一個供奉的姿勢
Out like an offering.
擺一個飛機的姿勢
Fly like a plane.
把胳膊舉起來
Raise your arms up.
擺成一個三角形
Together like a triangle.
擺一個供奉的姿勢
Out like an offering.
擺一個飛機的姿勢
Fly like a plane.
把胳膊舉起來
Raise your arms up.
擺成一個三角形
Together like a triangle.
擺一個供奉的姿勢
Out like an offering.
擺一個飛機的姿勢
Fly like a plane.
把胳膊舉起來
Raise your arms up.
擺成一個三角形
Together like a triangle.
擺一個供奉的姿勢
Out like an offering.
-擺一個飛機的姿勢  -快點
- Fly like a plane. - Faster!
把胳膊舉起來
Raise your arms up.
擺成一個三角形
Together like a triangle.
擺一個供奉的姿勢
Out like an offering.
-擺一個飛機的姿勢  -再快點
- Fly like a plane. - Faster!
把胳膊舉起來
Raise your arms up.
擺成一個三角形
Together like a triangle.
擺一個供奉的姿勢
Out like an offering.
擺一個飛機的姿勢
- Fly like a plane. - Faster!
把胳膊舉起來  擺成一個三角形
Raise your arms up, together like a triangle.
擺一個供奉的姿勢  擺一個飛機的姿勢
Out like an offering, fly like a plane.
好了好了  夠了
All right, all right, all right, that's enough.
停停停
Stop, stop, stop.
就選他了
He's the guy.
讓其他人回家
Send everyone else home.
就是他了
It's him.
天吶
Wow.
恭喜你
Ah, congratulations.
跟我來
Come with me.
這樣...
So...
這是迷怪
This is Pooka.
你覺得怎么樣
What do you think?
它...
It's, um...
可愛
Cute?
拜托
Come on!
這個玩意兒不止是可愛  好嗎
This motherfucker's more than cute, baby.
拜托
Come on!
這個玩意兒不止是可愛  好嗎
This motherfucker's more than cute, baby!
對吧
Right?
太棒了
It's amazing.
這是主要的功能
It's a main feature.
它會重復你說過的話
He listens to what you say and repeats it.
但是有意思的在于
But here's the hook.
他是無法預料的
He's unpredictable.
迷怪選擇錄下并重復的話
You don't choose what Pooka's gonna record
不是由你選擇  而是由它自己
and repeat, Pooka does.
他有調皮的設定和乖巧的設定
He's got a naughty setting and a nice setting,
但是你無法選擇它的心情
but you don't choose what mood he's gonna be in.
迷怪才能選
Pooka does.
但是你無法選擇它的心情
But you don't choose what mood he's gonna be in.
迷怪才能選
Pooka does.
我告訴你  測試下來
I'm telling you, this thing tested
這玩意完美翻了
through the roof.
它絕對能讓圣誕節翻個天
This is gonna rip Christmas a new asshole.
我不明白這和我有什么關系
I don't understand what this has to do with me.
我是個演員
I'm an actor.
伙計  你的人生要徹底改變了
Buddy, your life is about to change forever.
調皮的迷怪
Naughty Pooka.
這是不是很棒
Is this thing fucking amazing
還是說太他媽棒了
or is this thing fucking amazing?
你覺得怎么樣
What do you think?
看起來和那個玩具一樣
Looks just like the toy.
不不不  說反了
No, no, no, no, other way around.
是那玩具看起來和這個一樣
The toy looks like this.
是這個先來的
This came first.
你要我穿著這個嗎
So you want me to wear this?
伙計  我要你成為它
Buddy, I want you to be him.
我覺得肯定是誤會了
I think there's been a misunderstanding.
我是一名專業的演員
See, I am a professional actor.
所以你才會在這里
That's why you're here.
我們需要一個
We need somebody who can be
不僅僅只是穿著服裝的家伙
more than just a guy in a suit.
我們需要一個
We need somebody
能賦予他生命的人
who can bring him to life.
沒有你
Without you,
他什么都不是
he's nothing.
你都沒有量我的身材
You didn't take my measurements.
你怎么知道穿著能合適
How did you know it'd fit?
當然能合適了
Of course it fits!
這屬于你
It belongs to you.
感覺怎么樣
How does it feel?
感覺
It feels...
還行
okay.
Well, okay.
看來你們倆是天造地設啊
Seems like you two were made for each other.
轉過來讓我看看
Let's see you move around.
我怎么動
Uh, how do I move?
記得要你在試鏡時做的動作嗎
Remember the thing you did in your audition?
你試試
Try that.
把胳膊舉起來
Raise your arms up.
擺成一個三角形
Together like a triangle.
供奉的姿勢
Out like an offering.
擺一個飛機的姿勢
And then you fly like a plane.
把胳膊舉起來
You raise your arms up.
擺成一個三角形
Together like a triangle.
供奉的姿勢
Out like an offering.
擺一個飛機的姿勢
Fly like a plane.
把胳膊舉起來
Raise your arms up.
擺成一個三角形
Together like a triangle.
供奉的姿勢
Out like an offering.
擺一個飛機的姿勢
And then you fly like a plane.
你沒事吧
You okay?
怎么了  伙計
What's goin' on, man?
你沒事吧
You okay?
怎么了
What's goin' on?
上帝啊
Jesus Christ.
小心點  伙計
Watch it on that, man.
這玩意是要推銷給孩子的
We're trying to market this thing to children.
這個太緊了嗎
Is this too tight for you?
這算是什么測試
What the fuck kind of test was that?
-什么意思  -算了
- What do you mean? - Forget about it!
什么算了
Forget about what?
我沒有感覺
I'm not feeling it, okay?
你在做出最終決定前
Do you want to talk about numbers
要不要先討論一下酬勞
before you make your final decision?
我覺得你應該會對酬勞有感覺
I feel like you're gonna feel these numbers.
這有...
There's this, um...
匿名條款
There's this anonymity clause.
標準保密條款
Standard nondisclosure.
你不能說你是誰
You don't say who you are,
我們不會說你是誰
we don't say who you are.
這樣能保護我們雙方
Protects us both.
沒人會知道是我
No one'll know it's me?
絕對不會
No, never.
這都是信任問題
It's about trust.
其他推銷這些玩具的人
And, um, everyone else who promotes these toys,
都要簽一份這個嗎
they sign one of these?
什么意思
What do you mean?
其他演員
The other actors.
什么其他演員
What other actors?
我以為
I thought you said this was gonna be huge.
完美翻了
Tested through the roof.
就是圣誕大促銷吧
It's a Santa' n' the all thing, right?
還有幾個迷怪
How many other Pookas are there?
威爾遜
Wilson,
只有你  好嗎
this is all you, okay?
一個迷怪  一個你
One Pooka, one you.
這是一個夢想
This is a dream.
太好了  太好了
Yes, yes!
公司絕對會愛上你  所以
Corporate is gonna love you, so...
休息去吧
get comfortable,
接下來就回去好好休息  給
take the rest of the day off. Here you go!
不不不不不
Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
不不不不
No, no, no, no.
什么都沒有丟
And nothing's missing,
什么都沒有嗎
nothing at all?
是的
No.
你知道他們是怎么進來的嗎
Do you have an idea how they got in?
門上著鎖  窗戶關著
The door was locked, the windows were closed.
我完全不知道
I have no idea.
我告訴你  親愛的
I'm telling you, darling,
你應該報警
you should call the police.
沒有東西被偷
Nothing was stolen.
很多破碎的東西是無法彌補的
A lot was broken that you can't un-break.
這樓里以前發生過這種事嗎
Has this ever happened in this building before?
在我印象里
First time I can remember.
這是個安靜的地方
It's a rather quiet place.
我明天去找個鄰居
I'll borrow a vacuum tomorrow
借一個吸塵器
from one of the neighbors
處理掉被我們遺漏的玻璃碎渣
for any bits of glass that we've missed.
你在房間里就穿著鞋子吧
Meanwhile, you keep your shoes on inside.
放松點  親愛的
Relax, love.
我知道有人闖入很可怕
I know, break-ins can be scary.
讓你在自己的家里感到害怕
They make you feel scared in your own home,
但是沒人會回來的
but no one is coming back.
結束了
It's over.
迷怪來了
真漂亮  威爾遜
Oh, it's beautiful, Wilson.
這樣就算我不在
That way you won't feel alone,
你也不會感到孤單了
even when I'm not here.
好了  我要去工作了
All right, off to work.
你的新工作是什么
What is this new job?
你都沒怎么和我提過
You've hardly told me anything about it.
是得穿著頭套的
Uh, it's just this thing in a costume.
相信我  沒什么意思的
Trust me, there's nothing interesting about it.
回頭見了
I'll see you.
迷怪
調皮還是乖巧
你永遠不知道迷怪會怎么做
警告  非常好玩
圣誕老人列了一張單子
He's making a list,
迷怪  圣誕節的新寵
反復核查
he's checking it twice,
但就算他也分不出
but even Santa won't be able to tell
今年最火爆的玩具
if this year's new hottest toy
到底是調皮還是乖巧
is naughty or nice.
認識一下迷怪
Meet Pooka,
一個有點調皮的
a cute, friendly little teddy bear
可愛迷人小熊
with a bit of a naughty side.
還是說應該是有點可愛的調皮小熊
Or is it the other way around?
你說什么我就說什么
撓撓我的肚子
警告  非常好玩
迷怪
調皮還是乖巧
這款玩具的推出
The toy has surprised
讓其最大的競爭對手都被打了個措手不及
even its biggest competitors
這種新奇的營銷和宣傳策略
and is making waves with its unusual marketing
讓它席卷市場
and distribution strategy.
公司不愿意透露這款玩具的開發靈感
The company won't say how the toy was conceived,
賈斯汀下一個能見迷怪
或者其獲利情況
or how many units have been made,
只表示他們期望
just that they expect them
拿到了最后一張售罄前的迷怪海報
娜塔莉和杰姬絕對會很開心
能在圣誕前一天
to sell out entirely
全部售出
well before Christmas morning.
聽好了
And get this:
迷怪  圣誕節的新寵
如果你也想要一個
If you want one,
只有一個地方能夠買到
there's only one place you'll be able to get it,
那就是在我的身后
and it's right here behind me
就在迷怪中心
at the Pooka Pop-Up.
迷怪中心  開業中
我愛你  迷怪
I love you, Pooka.
I love you, Pooka!
我喜歡烏龜
I like turtles.
I like turtles!
我喜歡烏龜
I like turtles.
I like turtles!
我喜歡烏龜
大家伙
Okay, everyone.
抱歉  壞消息
So sorry, sad news,
迷怪鎮的壞消息
sad news out of Pooka Town.
我們全部賣光了
We are all sold out.
沒錯  我們明早九點會重新開業
Yeah, so we'll be back open tomorrow at 9 A. M.
一定要回來  我們會進更多的迷怪
Come back, we got a lot more Pookas for sale.
怎么了  伙計
What's up, man?
好看的媽媽們嗎
Ah, cruisin' moms?
稍等一下
Give me a second.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
這不是我給你的哦
This didn't come from me.
梅拉尼·伯恩斯
房地產商
看房日
你下了我一跳
You scared me.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
我是威爾遜
I'm Wilson.
梅拉尼
Melanie.
見到你很高興
It's a pleasure to meet you.
我只是想來看看房子
I, uh, was just hoping to have a look at the house
如果你不忙的話
if you're not too busy.
沒問題  我能帶你轉一圈
Of course, I will give you the official tour.
你是第一個
You will be the first.
這幢房是1966年建成的
The house was built in '66.
中世紀中的翹楚
It's a mid-century gem.
現代  明亮
Modern, bright.
光線非常充足
Filled with tons of light.
四間臥室  四間浴室
Four bedroom, four bath
如果你有需要的話還有很多公用空間
with plenty of communal space if you need it.
說到這個
Speaking of which,
這里是家庭活動室
this is the family room.
你在這市場里多久了
How long have you been in the market?
什么市場
The...the market?
房地產市場
Real estate market.
你找房子多久了
How long you've been looking.
對
Right.
我應該不算在市場里
Yeah, I'm not sure I am in the market.
我...我只是突然感興趣
The...the listing just caught my eye,
而已
I think.
就是有時候突然看到一個地方
You know how you just see someplace and...
想想自己住在里面
you picture yourself living there.
我的確喜歡想象我自己
I do like to see myself
住在我推銷的房子里
in all the places that I show.
就算是不好的房子嗎
Even the bad ones?
沒有不好的房子
There are no bad ones,
只有適不適合
only right or wrong fits.
這話說得好
That's very good, um,
說得非常專業
that's very...professional.
你很擅長
Was nicely done.
那么你是干什么的
So, what do you do?
我是一名演員
I'm an actor.
真棒
Oh, nice.
這里可是洛杉磯
Well, it's LA.
我其實只能算得上群演
I'm not much more than a walking cliche.
你看上去很眼熟
You look familiar.
你不用這么說的
Well, you don't have to say that.
不  真的
No, it's true!
你有演過什么我看過的角色嗎
Uh, anything I would have seen you in?
有可能嗎
Yeah. Maybe.
那你覺得這個廚房怎么樣
So, what do you think of this kitchen?
全新的花崗巖和碎石裝飾臺面
Brand new granite and Caesarstone countertops,
全新的設備
new appliances,
還有這風景
and the view.
還不賴
Not too bad.
你好像已經在心里規劃
You look like you're having a vision.
這房子能裝修成什么樣子
Seeing how this house could be.
對
Yeah.
那么
So, uh...
這里應該是客廳吧
I guess this is the living room.
對吧
Right?
我要在這個角落
Yeah, I'd put a big leather couch
放一張大皮沙發
in the corner over there.
艾墻上掛一張巨大的畫
A...huge piece of art on the wall,
要...現代的
something...modern,
抽象的
abstract,
奇怪的
strange.
沒錯
Yeah.
住在這里
Someone could...
肯定能過上幸福的生活
could really make a nice life here.
一個人住會不會太空曠了
It is kind of big for one person, you know?
希望不會永遠是一個人
Hopefully it won't always be just one.
你想出價嗎
Do you want to make an offer?
也許吧
Maybe.
但是  聽著
But listen,
我一般不會這么做
I don't normally do this.
我發誓  但是
I swear, but...
我能請你一起吃個晚餐嗎
could I maybe ask you out for dinner?
有點過了
That's a little forward.
我知道
I know,
但是你不是經常能碰到
but it's not always that you meet someone
讓你驚艷的人
that you think might be amazing.
認識你真的很高興  威爾遜
It was really nice meeting you, Wilson.
我就不送你出去了
I'll let you see yourself out.
聯系我
Call me sometime.
她真的好棒  雷德
Oh, she's amazing, Red.
你知道那種你遇見了一個人卻覺得
You know that feeling when you meet someone
你早就和她相識的感覺嗎
and it's like you've known them forever?
天啊  她很風趣
Oh, God, she's funny
她是那么...美
and she's so...beautiful,
我...我感覺好棒
and...and I just feel amazing.
我感覺一切都走上正軌
I feel like everything is working out.
我感覺我能做到我想做的人和事
I feel like I can do anything I want.
那是什么聲音
What's that?
什么什么聲音
What's what?
那種撞擊的聲音
That pounding noise.
我什么都聽不到
I can't hear anything.
我想起來我把什么東西落在我的房間了
I just remembered I...I left something in my room.
我去拿一下  好嗎
I'm gonna go and grab it, okay?
我馬上回來
I'll be back in just a sec.
好的
Okay.
我
Uh, I, um,
我做飯燒傷了我的手
I burnt my hands, uh, cooking.
我得把手包起來
I've got to keep them covered for a while
才能痊愈
to allow them to heal.
真帥氣
Handsome.
他會做飯
He cooks.
我真幸運
Lucky me.
我...我是在煮意大利面時
Well, I, uh...I burnt my hands
燒傷了自己的手
cooking a pot of spaghetti,
但是  我是說
but, I mean...
我喜歡你
I like the way
詮釋的樣子
that you're spinning it
聽起來好多了
much, much better.
我還需要了解你的什么呢
What else should I know about you?
你在笑什么
What are you smiling about?
真是太好了
This has been nice.
認識你
Meeting you.
如此意外
Unexpected.
對吧
Right?
目前為止都很棒
So far so good.
我想親吻你
I want to kiss you,
但是
but...
我覺得我需要許可
I think I might need permission.
許可了
Permission granted.
不是你的
Not from you.
那祝你好運了
Good luck with that.
這是今天的最后一個了
It's the last one today.
實在是太感激你了  伙
Really appreciate this, man.
謝謝
Thank you.
給泰
你們家真溫馨
Wow, this is, uh, this is a nice home.
謝謝你
Thank you.
過不了多久就亂了
It's temporary, though.
你的圣誕樹呢
Where's your tree?
我們沒有
We don't have one.
也許今年就不擺了
Maybe we'll skip it this year.
我以為我在哈爾彭的圣誕集市上看到你了呢
I thought I saw you at the Christmas lot on Halpern.
不  你看錯了
No, not us.
這是給我的嗎
Is this for me?
不  不
Uh, nah, um, no.
這是
This is, uh...
這是給守門人的
This is for the gatekeeper.
是嗎
Ah, is that right?
泰
Ty?
過來一下
Come here for a sec.
泰  這是威爾遜
Ty, this is Wilson.
你好  先生
Hello, sir.
很有禮貌
That's...that's good manners.
我不干涉
I don't mess around.
你好  泰
Hello Ty.
我有東西要給你
I have somethin' for you,
如果你想要的話
if you want it.
我現在打開嗎  還是
Can I open it now, or?
對
Uh, yeah.
它說
It says it, uh,
它現在就想被打開
it wants to be opened now.
我覺得你說得對
I think you're right, it does.
就這一次
Just this one.
我操  媽媽  是迷怪
Holy crap, Mom, it's a Pooka!
不許說臟話  你們倆都是
Watch your mouth, both of you.
你該說什么
What do you say?
謝謝你  先生
Thank you, sir!
威爾遜
Wilson.
叫我威爾遜
Call me Wilson.
這種
Yeah, they, uh,
這種玩具會不按套路出牌
they can be a little unpredictable.
怎么了
What?
你很好  威爾遜
You're kind, Wilson.
他爸爸就絕對不會想到這種方面
Something his dad never would have thought of.
是嗎
No?
他不是那種爸爸
Not that kind of dad.
那他是那種爸爸
What kind of dad was he?
就是我不想提及的那種爸爸
Not the kind I want to talk about.
我不想提及他
I don't want to talk about him.
我不想再讓他毀了我的生活
I...don't want him to spoil my life anymore.
在這里等著
Wait here.
我馬上回來
I'll be right back.
別擔心
Don't worry.
我哪兒也不會去的
I'm not goin' anywhere.
今天干得不錯
Good job today.
你也是
You too.
要去喝一杯嗎
You want to get out of here, get a drink?
你...你去吧
Uh, you...you go ahead.
我...我就
I'll...I'm just gonna
在這兒待一會
hang out here for a bit.
好吧
Okay.
All right.
保重
Take care.
謝謝你
Thank you.
不僅僅是今天
Not just for today,
或者這工作  而是...
or the gig, but...
為這一切
for everything.
沒事
Of course.
保重
Take care.
不  那...不
Oh...that the...no, no!
不
No!
天啊  你...你怎么了
Dearie me, what-- what's wrong with you?
親愛的  進來
Oh, love, come in.
進來
Come in.
我去燒水
I'll put the kettle on.
我媽媽經常說
There's nothing in the world
沒有什么事是一壺好茶
that a good cuppa can't fix,
解決不了的
as my mum used to say.
不過這當然是個謊言了
Of course, that's a lie, though, isn't it?
有的謊言反而能幫助你度過一些難關  對吧
Some lies help you get through things, don't they?
畢竟她就是靠濃茶安穩度過了閃電戰
Good, strong tea got her through the Blitz, after all.
我覺得我有點問題
I think there's something wrong with me.
我們都有問題  親愛的
there's something wrong with all of us, love.
不  雷德  我...
No, Red, I'm...
我的記憶出現空白
I'm losing time, and...
我失控了
I'm losing control.
一切都沒事
Things are all right...
對吧
right?
我有工作
I have this job,
遇見一個女孩
and this girl, and...
感覺
and it feels...
真的很棒
really good.
但是  這個東西  這...
But then, there's this-- this thing, this...
另一個東西...
this other thing, this...
這么危險
danger.
我覺得我記起為什么搬過來了
I feel like I remember why I moved here.
我是為了逃離
So I could get away.
逃離...痛苦
Away...from pain.
逃離給人造成痛苦
Away from causing pain.
每個人都有后悔的事  親愛的威爾遜
Everyone has regrets, Wilson darling.
生活很艱難
Life is hard.
我們都會犯錯
We make mistakes.
從現在起做出正確的決定
Make good choices now.
這是你的一切
That's all you have.
來啊
Come on!
來啊  來啊
Come on, come on!
太好了
Good, aw.
來啊  伙計們
Come on, guys!
迷怪  來啊
It's Pooka, come on!
來啊
Come on!
你今天玩的開心嗎
So did you have fun today?
我知道你想干什么
I know what you're up to.
我想干什么
What am I up to?
你想討好我
Trying to get on my good side
讓我媽媽更喜歡你
so that my mom will like you more.
你不用給我買禮物或者給我們買圣誕樹
You don't have to buy me things or get us a tree.
你只要陪著我們  對我們好
You just have to stick around and be nice.
我可以的
I can do that.
你不喜歡圣誕節嗎
You don't like Christmas?
對我們來說很復雜
Tricky time for us.
也許我能讓泰再愛上圣誕節
Maybe I can make Ty love Christmas again,
所以那周末我要給他辦個小圣誕派對
so I'm throwing him a little Christmas party at the end of the week.
叫很多他的朋友
Get a lot of his friends together,
放音樂啊  交換禮物啊
play some music, exchange gifts.
你媽媽
So your mom,
她和我說了你們下周要辦個圣誕派對
she told me about your Christmas party next week.
你高興嗎
Are you, uh, excited?
沒錯  肯定會和迷怪一起
Yeah. It's gonna be a Pooka thing.
多棒啊
How cool is that?
那你告訴我
Well, tell me this, now...
你想見見真正的迷怪嗎
would you like to meet Pooka for real?
-靠  當然了  -我聽到了
- Hell yes! - I heard that!
就是這棵了
This is it.
就這棵嗎
That's it.
對  就是這棵了
Yeah, this is the one.
泰
Hey, Ty!
過來看看這棵
Come and have a look at this one.
不好意思  伙計
Excuse me, pal.
你能幫我們拍一張照嗎
Do you mind taking our picture?
當然了  伙計
Yeah, of course, man.
謝謝
Thank you.
好的
Okay.
看看這璀璨的燈光
Look at all the pretty lights...
你會傷害我媽媽嗎
Are you going to hurt my mom?
你會傷害我嗎
Are you going to hurt me?
梅拉尼
Melanie?
迷怪
你不用跟他保證的
You know, you didn't have to promise that.
他一整個早上都在和朋友們
He's been telling all his friends all morning
吹噓那東西會來參加他的派對
that that thing is coming to his party.
我知道你是好意  但是
I know you meant well, but...
到時候如果沒有來的話
he's going to be really embarrassed
他會感覺很丟臉
when it doesn't happen.
為什么會沒有來呢
Why wouldn't it happen?
-拜托  -不  我和你說了
- Come on. - No, I told you.
我有關系
I have connections.
我和你說了  你為什么不相信我
I told you, why-- why wouldn't you trust me?
我相信你  只是
I trust you, it's just...
你確定嗎
are you sure?
你不用為了我而承諾太多
You don't have to overpromise to impress me.
不  我知道
No, I know!
我不是想要給他空歡喜
I'm not trying to put things in his head.
好嗎  絕對會來的
Okay? It's going to happen.
好的
Okay.
迷怪
Pooka!
媽媽  迷怪來了
Mom, Pooka's here!
你敢信嗎  他在我家呢
Can you believe he's here at my house?
真是太棒了
Pretty awesome.
對吧
Right?
我覺得還行吧
Yeah, it's okay, I guess.
你...你跟他說過話嗎
Have you--have you gotten to talk to him?
它是給小孩玩的  有什么大不了的
He's for little kids, what's the big deal?
你爸爸不在這里
Your dad isn't here.
那是什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
就...誰都知道你爸爸的事
Just--everybody knows about your dad.
救...
Help...
我不知道
Yeah, I don't know.
我不是很能理解發生了什么
I really don't understand what happened.
不
No.
他也不說什么
He's not saying much either.
你沒事吧  伙計
You okay, buddy?
很抱歉我今天沒有來
I'm sorry I wasn't able to make it today.
沒事
It's okay.
我習慣了
I'm used to it.
你能告訴我發生了什么嗎
Can you tell me what happened?
威爾遜
Wilson.
我看到了他做的事
I saw what he did.
我知道他是誰
I'm pretty sure I know who he is.
我真的太害怕了
I was really scared.
他們嚇壞了
They're livid.
我應該過來的
I should have been there.
-真希望你當時能在場  -我很抱歉
- I wish you had been. - I'm sorry...
變成了這樣
that it went so wrong.
我們都希望泰能覺得那個派對很特別
We both wanted the party to be special for Ty.
那家伙是誰啊
Who was that guy?
-什么  -穿那身衣服的家伙
- What? - That guy in the costume?
我真是不明白怎么會讓這種家伙
I just don't understand how someone like that
-跟小孩一起  -你是在怪我嗎
- could be around kids. - Are you blaming me?
不  我只是不明白怎么會發生這種事
No, I just don't understand what happened.
僅此而已
That's all.
威爾遜  你看上去非常冷淡
Wilson, you just seem kind of passive,
當時真的很可怕
and it was really awful,
我只是不明白  好嗎
and I just don't understand, all right?
孩子們很喜歡那個玩具
The kids love that toy.
我只是以為請那個玩偶來
I just thought that having the character there
和孩子們互動會非常特別
interacting with them, that it would be special.
-我明白  -我只想為泰做一些好事
- I get that. - I just wanted to do something nice for Ty.
我怎么知道會發生這種事
How was I supposed to know something like that would happen?
-我不是那個意思  -我只是想
- That's not what I meant. - I just wanted to do
為你和泰做一些好事
something nice for you and Ty!
我只想那樣
That's all I want.
在哪里
Where is it?
什么在哪里
Where is what?
那棵樹
The tree.
-什么樹  -上帝啊  梅拉尼
- What tree? - Christ, Melanie!
如果你不喜歡那棵該死的樹
If you didn't like the goddamned tree,
你可以直接告訴我
you could have just told me.
別這樣跟我說話
Don't talk to me like that!
-你到底怎么回事  -我感覺
- What has gotten into you? - I feel like...
這是信任問題  我感覺
like it's about trust, I feel like
你不信任我
you don't trust me.
你沒有告訴我真相
You don't tell me the truth.
-我沒有告訴你什么的真相  -一切
- What don't I tell you the truth about? - Everything!
關于那棵樹  泰的爸爸
About the tree, Ty's dad...
他和這一切有什么關系
What does he have to do with any of this?
他還在你們生活中嗎[照片上]
Is he still in the picture?
他是泰的爸爸  他不在我們生活中
Well, he's Ty's dad, he's not in the picture
但他在照片上
but he's in the picture.
事情就是這樣  沒有那么簡單
That's the way it works, it's not that simple.
沒錯  人人都知道泰的爸爸
Right, everybody knows about Ty's dad.
除我之外人人都知道他
Everybody knows about him but me!
請你馬上離開這里
You need to leave now.
我
I'm...
別碰我
Don't touch me.
離開
Leave.
快點
Now.
迷怪
迷怪故障導致大范圍回收
本季度最熱的玩具
The hottest toy of the season
帶來了最深的失望
has turned into its biggest disappointment.
洛杉磯各地
Countless malfunctioning Pookas
沒用
返廠了無數出故障的迷怪
have been returned throughout Los Angeles,
垃圾
去他媽的迷怪
父母們抱怨原先大熱的
with parents complaining that the popular
"調皮或乖巧"的玩具突然壞了
"Naughty or Nice" toys are suddenly broken,
最大的失望
它們全都只會用奇怪的聲音
all of them saying nothing but
重復一段原先錄好的話
one bizarre prerecorded phrase.
看看這璀璨的燈光
Look at all the pretty lights,
Look at all the pretty lights.
先生  你覺得迷怪怎么樣
Sir, how do you feel about Pooka?
簡直就是一個廢物
It was a total rip-off.
日日夜夜
All day, all night,
只會重復
it just kept saying the same thing
一樣的話
over and over.
我退回了我的錢
Yeah, I-- I got my money back,
那我浪費的時間呢  這簡直是胡扯
but where's my time? This is bullshit!
-沒錯  -這簡直是胡扯
- Yeah! - This is bullshit!
我的時間呢
Where is my time?
我們要我們的錢
We want our money back!
迷怪中心  停止營業
直到有新的消息
伙計
Hey, man!
謝謝你把這個帶過來  非常感激
Thanks for bringing this by, appreciate it.
迷怪
調皮還是乖巧
你看上去不大好  怎么了
You don't look so good, man, what's going on?
我要和你談談
I need to talk to you.
我覺得公司搞錯了
Listen, I think corporate has got it wrong
我們得繼續下去
and we just need to keep going.
你在說什么  伙計
What are you talking about, man?
都回收了  公關危機
There's been a recall, the PR's terrible.
已經回不去了
There's no coming back from that.
你不能讓幾個小小的意外毀了一切
You can't just let a few fucking incidents ruin everything!
那不僅僅只是幾個小意外  威爾遜
It's more than a few incidents, Wilson.
那些玩具完蛋呢
The toys are busted.
已經沒有人想買了
Nobody wants to buy them anymore.
事實上  還好你把這些帶過來
In fact, I'm glad you brought this,
因為我可得拿回去了
'cause I gotta take it back.
等等  等等
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
怎么了  伙計
What's going on, man?
這不屬于你
This doesn't belong to you.
已經完了
It's done!
伙計
Hey, man.
好好休息休息
Take some time for yourself.
出城玩玩什么的
Get out of town or something.
過好你的日子
Go live life.
找兄弟們喝幾杯
Go have some beers with your bros.
我必須穿上這個
I need to be inside it.
你得控制你自己
You gotta get a grip.
接受一切的結束  伙計
It's okay for this to be over, man!
別來煩我  走開
Leave me alone, just go away!
小梅  拜托  我需要解釋一下
Mel, please, I need to explain!
小梅
Mel?
我要和你談談
I need to talk to you.
你好  親愛的
Hello, love.
上帝啊  雷德
Jesus Christ. Red.
我很抱歉  親愛的
I'm sorry, love.
你來晚了
You're too late.
你該離開了
It's time for you to go.
我是梅拉尼  請留言
Hi, it's Melanie, leave a message.
梅拉尼  是我  威爾遜
Hi, Melani, it's me, Wilson.
請聽我說
Please listen to this.
我很想你
I miss you, and,
而且我明白
and I understand, um,
我欠你一個道歉
I owe you an apology.
真正的道歉
A real one, and, um...
我明白你為什么把我推開
I understand why you pushed me away
你為什么會害怕
and why you were scared.
但我想告訴你  從今以后一切都會不一樣了
But I want you to know that things are gonna be different now.
我之前很迷茫
I was confused.
但我想重新開始
But I want to start over.
我希望我們能成為一家人
And I want us to be a family.
我很擔心你  而且
I'm worried about you, and, um...
我準備好成為一個更好的人了
I am ready to be a better man.
給梅拉尼
梅拉尼  是我  威爾遜
Melanie, it's me, Wilson.
請聽我說
Please listen to this.
我很想你
I miss you and, uh...
而且我明白  我欠你一個道歉
and I understand, um, I owe you an apology.
哥們  看著點路  伙計
Dude, watch where you're going, buddy.
但我想告訴你  從今以后一切都會不一樣了
And I want you to know that things are gonna be different now.
你什么毛病  伙計
What is your problem, man?
What's your problem, man, huh?
我之前很迷茫
I was confused.
但我想重新開始
I wanna start over.
我希望我們能成為一家人
I want us to be... a family.
我很擔心你  而且
I'm worried about you and, um,
我準備好成為一個更好的人了
I am ready to be a better man.
你需要幫助  伙計
You need help, man.
不不不不
No, no, no, no,
不不不不不
no, no, no, no, no, no, no!
-我們走  -不  你們在干什么
- Let's go. - No, what are you doing?
你們在干什么
What are you doing?
不  那是我
No, that's me!
那是我
That's me!
去他媽的迷怪
上帝啊
Holy shit.
威爾遜
Wilson.
發生了什么
What happened?
你做了什么
What did you do?
他們拿走了  伙計
They took it, man.
他們拿走了
They took it!
他們拿走什么
They took what?
我的頭
My head!
上帝啊  做些什么
Jesus Christ, do something.
我感覺不到迷怪了
I can't feel Pooka.
威爾遜
Wilson?
伙計
Buddy?
根本就沒有迷怪
There is no Pooka.
這是用來賣玩具的噱頭
It's an invention to sell toys.
這套衣服里的是你
It's you in a costume.
只有你
It's just you.
一直以來都只有你
It's always been just you.
不  不
No, no!
不
No!
住手
Stop!
不  不
No, no!
老實說  每年這種時候都經常會有這種事
We see it a lot this time of year, to be honest.
有沒有...
Was there a...
打斗的痕跡
was there a struggle?
唯一的打斗是跟她的酒瓶
The only struggle was with the bottle
還有五層高樓
and five floors.
你們必須查出是誰干的
You need to find who did this to her.
我想我現在就看著她呢
Pretty sure I'm looking at that person right now.
不  你錯了
No, you're wrong.
我知道你是誰
I know exactly who you are!
不
No...
不  不要動他們
no, not them!
不要動他們
Not them!
操
Oh, fuck!
喂
Hello?
泰  你沒事吧
Ty, are you okay?
我們要去木場
We're going to the tree lot.
-我們需要一棵新的圣誕樹  -泰  聽我說
- We need to get a new tree. - Ty, Ty, listen to me.
有東西去找你們了
Something is coming for you, okay?
你們有危險  聽我說
You're in danger, all right? Listen to me.
泰
Ty?
迷怪時間到
梅拉尼
Melanie?
泰
Ty?
不會再讓你傷害任何人了
You are not going to hurt anyone anymore!
You are not going to hurt anyone anymore.
不會再讓你傷害任何人了
小梅
Mel?
小梅  是我  威爾遜
Mel, it's me, Wilson.
對不起
I'm sorry.
我對我之前的表現很抱歉  但是
I'm so sorry for how I acted before, but
一切都會不一樣了
it's all gonna be different now,
一切都會好了
everything's gonna be okay now,
一切都變了
everything's changed.
我變了
I've changed.
小梅
Mel?
抱歉  您撥打的電話
We're sorry, you have reached a number
已停機
that has been disconnected
或者是空號
or is no longer in service.
如果你認為你打錯了電話
If you feel you have reached this recording in error,
請重新核查號碼并撥打
please check the number and try your call again.
梅拉尼
Melanie?
泰
Ty?
梅拉尼
Melanie?
泰
Ty.
回你的房間
Go to your room.
我不想這么做
I don't want to do this.
梅拉尼  我只想談談...
Melanie, I just want to discuss--
你不想談
You don't want to discuss it.
你想讓我認為你不是騙子
You want to convince me that you're not a liar.
在我發火之前
So before I lose my shit,
滾出我的房子
get out of my house.
這也是我的房子
It's my house too!
你想喊多大聲就喊多大聲
Yell as much as you want.
-但是你別想怪我  -你知道一直被說是騙子
- But you blaming me is bullshit. - Do you know what it's like
是什么感受嗎
to constantly be called a liar?
你知道那種感覺嗎
Do you know how that feels?
你知道那是什么感覺嗎
Do you know what it's like?
你知道這讓我感覺有多蠢嗎
Do you know how stupid that makes me feel?
你在乎嗎
Do you even fucking care?
操  別...
Fuck! Don't--
別他媽背對著我
don't fucking turn your back on me!
該死
Dammit!
泰
Ty.
對...對不起
I'm--I'm sorry.
伙計  這...
Buddy, this...
這是個意外
this was an accident.
好嗎
Okay?
不過別擔心  我們能去買個新的
But don't worry, we're gonna get a new one.
好嗎
All right?
我
I'm...
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
我們馬上就去買個新的
We'll get a new one right away, okay?
我保證那肯定會是最棒的
It'll be the best one ever, I promise.
木場還是開著的
The lot will still be open.
我們可以過去然后買棵...
You know, we can just head down and get--
買棵新的
and get a new one
我們一起  好嗎
together, okay?
不
No.
別聽他的
Don't listen to him.
明明不行  他在撒謊
It's not okay. He's lying.
他只是想讓他自己感覺好一點
He just wants to make himself feel better.
會很特別的
It'll be special.
親愛的  去拿外套
Sweetie, go get your jacket.
最后一次了  威爾遜
This is the last time, Wilson.
結束了
It's over.
好吧
Yeah, okay.
喂   泰  泰  你沒事吧
Hello? Hello, Ty? Ty, are you okay?
我們要去木場
We're going to the tree lot.
我們需要一棵新的圣誕樹
We need to get a new tree.
有東西去找你們了
Something is coming for you, okay?
你們有危險  聽我說
You're in danger, all right?
-聽我說  -走吧
- Listen to me. - Come on.
我們一起
Stay with me.
對不起
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry!
慢點  威爾遜
Slow down, Wilson.
我們得趕在關門前趕到
Gotta get there on time.
對吧  泰
Right, Ty?
我們要買他們最棒的樹
Want to get the best tree they have.
看  泰
Look, Ty.
看看這璀璨的燈光
Look at all the pretty lights.
梅拉尼
Melanie?
泰
Ty?
沒事  有我們呢  有我們呢
All right, we got you, we got you.
好了  伙計
All right, buddy.
堅持住  伙計
Stay with me, buddy.
堅持住
Stay with me.
放松
Just relax.
好吧  好吧  好吧
All right, all right, all right.
看看這璀璨的燈光
Look at all the pretty lights.
放松
Just relax.
看看這璀璨的燈光
Look at all the pretty lights.
放松
Just relax.
看看這璀璨的燈光
Look at all the pretty lights.